Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Electronics/Telecommunication]

Sai Chaitanya Ramineni 🚹 premium



Senior Software Engineer seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, Application Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Solution

Architecture, ReactJS, PHP, AngularJS, Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SQL

Server, MySQL, Mongo DB



Current Designation: Senior Software Engineer -PHP Total Experience: 6 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Tekion Corp

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Hyderabad

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: ReactJS,PHP,AngularJS,Python,JavaScript,HTML,CSS,SQL Server,MySQL,Mongo DB, Software

Development, Application Programming, Application Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Solution

Architecture

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: Jan-Mar 2021 Last Modified: Jan-Mar 2021

Summary

Bachelors from NIT Warangal in ECE and Software Development professional with extensive years of experience in Web Development including HTML, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, PHP, Ajax, Angular Js, Angular 2 and Python Automations etc. Extensive experience in full software development life cycle process including requirements, design, coding, testing, and maintenance. Proven track record of designing and implementing flexible solutions that support frequent user interfaces and functionality changes.

Work Experience

Tekion Corp as Senior Software Engineer -PHP May 2019 to Till Date

Gather Requirements, design and develop various accounting modules as a part of a DMS tool built for auto motive dealerships and respective subsidiaries based on React js.

Lead development of critical financial tools and their integrations with multiple OEM's in short time.

Soroco as Senior Software Engineer Jul 2018 to Mar 2019

Develop robust client-side applications using Angular 6. Some of them include Dashboards and portals to accept inputs for data processing.

Develop custom proprietary front-end library consisting of UI components which are common across various projects, to enable further projects to use the library, hence reduce the time of development and standardizing the code and reducing peer dependency.

Develop UI template library consisting of html components for reuse and quick development.

Develop a library of functions used across projects to reduce effort, reuse the code and thus follow a standard code principle across multiple projects in the company.

Woovly as Software Engineer Feb 2017 to Dec 2017

Monitor and develop internal tools, both UI and backend automations using python.

Fetch data from multiple sources structured and unstructured, process the data and make an analysis

Being a social networking platform, I used to Manage the Email Campaign and Social Media Marketing planning and scheduling.

Working on Personalizing the content particular to a user to increase open and click ratio in email campaigns.

Investigate on SEO optimization techniques.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from National Institute of Technology (NIT), Warangal in 2014

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used	Experience
php, Python		
JavaScript, C++		
HTML (5), CSS		
XML, JSON		
SQL Server		
MySQL, Mongo DB		
React JS, Angular 2		
Angular Js, Jquery		
Bootstrap, Selenium		
Apache, IIS		
Data Structures, OOPS		

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Telugu				
Kannada				

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time